Muhammad Asad

Frontend Web Developer

💌 masad.jkb@gmail.com 📞 +923057637663 👂 Multan, Pkistan 🛗 26th August 2000

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/techasadkhan/

PROFILE

An enthusiastic Frontend Web Developer With Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology. I have been Designing and Developing Web Applications for the Last Year . These are all highly optimised and maintained with structured code which allow other developers to easliv understand the projects. Determining the Structure of Web Pages. Ensuring User Experience determines design choices. Developing features to enhance the user experience. Ensuring web design is optimised for smartphone. Building reuseable code for future use. Utilize a variety of markup language to write web .Maintaining Brand consistency throughout the design. String Problem Solving and troubleshooting skill

EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Information Technology, **Bahauldin Zakariya University**

September 2019 - May 2023 Multan, Pakistan CGPA: 3.5/4.0

FSC Pre Engineering (HSSC), **Punjab Group of Colleges**

July 2017 – April 2019 | Multan, Pakistan

Grades: 85%

SKILLS

JavaScript | ReactJS | Redux | JQuery Bootstrap | Tailwind Css | Material UI CSS3 | Html5 | Responsiveness | OOP Git&GitHub | Restful Service/APIs Wordpress

PROJECTS

Grilli-Master, Food Ordering website

Develope a grilli-master Javascript Food Ordering Website learning responsiveness, making custom Slider, Preloader, Parallex effect real world use of browser events

Spotify Clone, Music player website

Create a fully functional Music Player Website learning working with Arrays how to use loops, DOM Manipulation, use of arrow functions and Conditions

XCrypto, React Currency App

Develope a Currency app that shows the currency of different countries with graph ratio between past week and past month by using Api's

■ PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ICTVision, Internee as Web Developer

June 2022 – August 2022 | Multan, Pakistan My role was Transforming Figma designs to Responsive UserFirendly Interfaces and developing Interactive real world Projects Utilizing javascript knowledge to make websites Functional

SandyApps,

Internee Frontend Web Developer

May 2023 – present | Multan, Pakistan Focuses on honing my React.js skills by working on small to medium-sized projects or contributing to ongoing projects. Learn how to efficiently utilize React.js features, such as state management, event handling, and component lifecycle methods, to create interactive and responsive user interfaces. As a frontend React developer is responsible for writing clean and maintainable code, adhering to industry best practices and coding standards. Additionally collaborates with the backend development team to integrate frontend components with the backend APIs or services, ensuring smooth communication and data exchange between the user interface and the server.

LANGUAGES

Urdu

High Proficient in speaking and Writing

English

Good Proficiency, Conversational

TravelNest.

A MERN Stack tour Booking App

It was Full Stack Tour Booing web app developed by me. My Main focous was to learn the advanced react concept in this project. I learnt how to connect Database in in our project and how we make routes in express and working with real api's. It was an amazing project for me, I learnt lot of things in this project.

Shopping Cart, E-Commerce shopping cart

Develop an e-commerce shopping cart where users can browse products, add them to the cart, and proceed to checkout. Use Redux to manage the state of the cart, including adding and removing items, updating quantities, and calculating the total price.



Badminton | Cricket | Coding

Problem Solving | Team Management